christiesrealestate.com 2016-04-02

# Privacy Policy Christie's International Real Estate

**CHRISTIE'S INTERNATIONAL REAL ESTATE, INC.   PRIVACY POLICY**

Christie's International Real Estate, Inc. and Christie’s International Real Estate Europe Limited (“we” or “us”) consider the privacy and protection of our clients' data, both corporate and personal, to be of utmost importance and we take robust measures to protect the security and integrity of all such information.

However, the law requires us to take particular steps in relation to the processing and protection of personal data.  To ensure that you feel confident about providing us with your personal information when communicating with us and using our services, we outline below our practices in relation to the collection and use of personal data.  This policy sets out the basis on which we will collect, use and process personal data. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully to ensure you understand how we handle your personal data; please also check this page from time to time as the Policy may be updated.

**INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM YOU**

We may collect and process the following information about you:

  * information you provide by filling in forms on our website ([www.christiesrealestate.com](http://www.christiesrealestate.com/)); and information given in hard copy form or by any other means providing: your name; date of birth; address; interests; marketing preferences; when appropriate your credit information; and any other personal information relevant to the services we provide. This information may be provided when you are registering interest, transacting with us, subscribing to our services or for newsletters or requesting information;
  * correspondence or other contacts you may have with us;
  * details of transactions you carry out through our website, and any communications by telephone;
  * details of your visits to our website including, but not limited to, traffic data, web logs or other communication data and the resources you access.

The information you provide to us will be used for processing transactions but may also be used for internal data processing, such as compiling statistical information about your interests and the use of [www.christiesrealestate.com](http://www.christiesrealestate.com/). As a service to you, we may also use this information to customize the content we offer on [www.christiesrealestate.com](http://www.christiesrealestate.com/).

 **SPECIFIC INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT VIA WWW.CHRISTIESREALESTATE.COM**

We may collect and process the following information obtained from your use of [www.christiesrealestate.com](http://www.christiesrealestate.com/).

  * **Cookies** A cookie is a simple text file that is stored on your computer or mobile device by a website’s server and only that server will be able to retrieve or read the contents of that cookie. Each cookie is unique to your web browser. It will contain some anonymous information such as a unique identifier and the site name and some digits and numbers. It allows a website to remember things like your preferences or what’s in your shopping basket. Using our website will result in us placing cookies on your computer in the 3 categories set out below.
    * Strictly necessary: These cookies are essential to enable you to move around the website and use its features, such as accessing secure areas of the website; many of the functions on our website will not work properly, or at all, if you do not allow these cookies to be used. We may therefore be unable to provide many of the services you may wish to request unless you accept the use of these cookies.
    * Performance: These cookies collect information about how visitors use a website, for instance which pages visitors go to most often. These cookies do not collect information that identifies a visitor: all information these cookies collect is aggregated and is therefore anonymous. The information is only used to improve how the website works.
    * Functionality: These cookies allow the website to remember choices you make (such as your user name, language or the region you are in) and provide enhanced, more personal features (for example, remembering changes you have made to text size and fonts).

If you reside outside the EU, we also use a fourth type of cookie for Targeting or Advertising:

  * Targeting or Advertising: We sometimes partner with third parties to deliver more relevant advertisements and to compile web statistics. These third parties may use cookies, web beacons and other tracking technology to monitor your visits to both Christie’s International Real Estate and other websites. They monitor your online behavior and identify website usage, helping advertisers show you advertising and content that is more relevant to you. Some examples of what Targeting and Advertising Cookies do: 
    * Provide advertisers with information about your visit to our websites so they can show you advertising that is relevant to you.
    * Limit the number of times you see an advertisement.
    * Help measure the effectiveness of an advertising campaign.

Don't worry - none of these cookies store personally identifiable information and we only use trusted advertising partners. Just so you know, these third parties will have their own privacy policies and they may be different from ours.

  * **IP Address  
**  
We may collect information about your computer, including your internet address, operating system and browser type when you visit us. Your internet address is used to help identify and gather statistical or demographic information about our customers generally. We also use this information for internal system administration to help diagnose problems with our servers, to administer our website and the customer or user experience./ul>

**HOW IS THIS PERSONAL INFORMATION USED?**

We will collect, record, store and use your personal data world-wide among the Christie’s group companies for clearly specified purposes, including but not limited to:

  * to enable you to purchase or sell real property through the affiliates of Christie's International Real Estate and unless you object, to advise you of services to market or to purchase real property;
  * carrying out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us;
  * notifying you about changes to our products and services;
  * ensuring that our website is presented in the most effective manner for you and your computer; and
  * selling or purchasing property or services.

We may contact you for the above purposes by telephone call, email, text or SMS messaging and other means.

**SHARING INFORMATION**

We will not share your personal data with anyone outside the Christie's International Plc group of companies other than in accordance with the law and as stated in this Policy. Each of the countries in which we operate has different privacy laws. Our Privacy Policy will reflect those.  We may from time to time however need to disclose your personal data to certain third parties.

  * **Anti-Money Laundering and Regulatory Authorities**

We may need to retain and disclose certain information about you to regulatory authorities and to appropriate agencies to conduct anti-money laundering and trade sanction checks and to assist with fraud prevention, in particular, in compliance with our AML obligations and in relation to trade sanctions. We will disclose this information as is required by law.

  * **Agents or Contractors of Christie's International Real Estate   **

From time to time, however, we may need to disclose certain personal information to our agents, sales associates and/or officers of designated affiliates of Christie’s International Real Estate or to contractors of Christie's International Real Estate in order to enable us to communicate with you or to customize the Website to better serve you. Where we do so it will be on the basis that these persons are required to keep the information confidential and secure, and will not use the information for any other purpose than to carry out the services they are performing for Christie's International Real Estate.

  * **Credit Agencies**

We may need to disclose certain personal information about you to credit agencies to conduct appropriate checks when you are transacting with us.

  * **Legal Disclosures**

While we will not voluntarily disclose your personal data we may disclose such information if we are required to do so by a valid Court Order, if we are lawfully requested by government or law enforcement authorities, if we are required to do so pursuant to other legal processes, or if it becomes necessary to protect the rights or property of Christie’s International Real Estate.

**SECURITY**

We will take all reasonable and appropriate steps to protect the security and integrity of all personal information provided to our website, or by any other means electronic or otherwise.

We will ensure that your personal data within Christie’s International Real Estate is suitably protected against both unauthorized physical and electronic access.  These measures include an electronic firewall and various other protection measures that involve virus scanning, installation of security patches, vulnerability testing, backup and recovery planning, employee training, security audits, and other steps designed to constantly improve the data protection posture. However, we cannot guarantee that information during transmission through the internet or any computer network is entirely safe from unauthorized intrusion, access or manipulation.  We will have no liability for disclosure of information due to errors or unauthorized acts of third parties.  In any event, where we believe personal data has been compromised, we will notify you of this. 

**YOUR RIGHTS**

You have the legal right to a copy of the information which we hold about you, including information on how this will be used and to ensure this information is accurate. You also have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes - you can exercise this right by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect data or at any time by contacting us at info@christiesrealestate.com.

 **EMAIL**  
In order to provide you with timely notice regarding new real property offered for sale, Christie's International Real Estate may send you email notices. To facilitate this service, we may note some of the pages you visit on our website.

At any time, you may discontinue this service by sending an email to [info@christiesrealestate.com](mailto:info@christiesrealestate.com) and requesting that your email address be removed from our lists.

 **THIRD PARTY WEBSITES**

The Christie's International Real Estate sites contain links to other Websites which are not operated by us.  The information you provide to us will not be transmitted to other websites. However, these websites may collect personal information about you in accordance with their own privacy policies.  Christie’s International Real Estate is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.

 **CONTACTING YOU**

In order to provide you with marketing information about our products and services, we may contact you by email, text, SMS or any other messaging service, telephone, fax and by post. At the bottom of any marketing emails you will have a clearly marked unsubscribe option from future mailings. In addition, you may at any time send an email to info@christiesrealestate.com asking for your name to be removed from our lists.

**WORLDWIDE TRANSFERS AND PROCESSING**

As a global organization, Christie’s International Real Estate may process your personal information as described above in countries outside of the EEA. Each of these countries has differing privacy laws offering different levels of protection for your personal information. Our Privacy Policy reflects these varying practices and we will act in accordance with this Policy in all jurisdictions we operate in. By providing your personal information to Christie’s International Real Estate, you consent to us processing your personal information in any jurisdiction, in accordance with this Policy

**FINDING LUXURY ESTATES FOR SALE**

Christie's International Real Estate provides users of this site the opportunity to receive information about real property offered for sale, which will require Christie’s International Real Estate to provide your email address(es) to our affiliate brokers.

If you do not wish to receive further email from the sender, please reply to the sender and request that they stop sending you such emails in the future. Christie's International Real Estate does not accept responsibility for any third party's use (or misuse) of this service.

**HOW LONG WILL CHRISTIE’S INTERNATIONAL REAL ESTATE KEEP MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

We will hold your information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant activity.

**CHANGES TO THIS POLICY**

We reserve the right to amend or update this Privacy Policy and any of our privacy practices at any time. We will notify users of this website by posting any updated policy on this page and such changes will be effective immediately and without further notice. Where appropriate, we may notify you directly of changes to the Privacy Policy either through email or a prominent notice on our website

 **CONTACT**

If you have any queries in relation to the use and protection of your personal data, please contact us at [info@christiesrealestate.com](mailto:info@christiesrealestate.com).

**Your Security Is Important to Us**

An increasingly common scam—called "phishing"—uses official-looking emails to deceive consumers into disclosing their personal information. The email often directs the recipient to a "look-alike" website of a legitimate business, tricking consumers into thinking they are responding to a valid request.

To avoid getting caught in any of these scams, it is recommended that you remember to take the actions below.  We cannot guarantee, however that by taking the below actions you will prevent dangerous spam causing you harm:

Keep your password secret and change it periodically.

Never give out your vital account information by email or telephone, unless you initiated the contact. **Christie's International Real Estate never sends emails asking for personal information.**

Whenever you wish to register at christiesrealestate.com, edit or add new information to your account, or set up a new Christie's International Real Estate, Inc. account, please make sure the URL address is as follows: http://www.christiesrealestate.com. You may want to add this URL to your browser's Favorites or Bookmarks menu.

Always end your secure session on the Internet completely by clicking the “Log Out” link and by closing your browser's window before you leave the computer.
